# Monica Lent

lent.monica@gmail.com monicalent.com github.com/mlent twitter.com/monicalent

Profile

Software engineer focusing on web technologies, with a diverse background that straddles both industry and research. I've worked in domains like fintech, natural language processing, and cloud services. I love learning new languages, dealing with interesting data, and creating things that are useful for others.

Experience

SumUp Berlin, Germany

Lead Front-end Engineer – 2016-Present

- Leading a distributed team of 15+ engineers developing SumUp's web products in areas such as architecture, implementation, and technical strategy.
- Directly managing and mentoring six engineers and two team leads.
- Collaborating with other members of Engineering and Product leadership to build autonomous cross-functional teams, ensure their success, and enable delivery.
- Evaluating technical viability of strategic merger and acquisition opportunities.
- · Recruiting, interviewing, hiring, and speaking at conferences.
- Continuing to work as an individual contributor on teams that need extra support.
- Skills and technologies: React.js, Node.js, Next.js, Jest, Enzyme, Docker

Senior Web Front-end Engineer – 2014-2016

- Developed numerous features for merchant-facing web application, such as signup, device purchase, and employee management.
- Led effort to apply best practices, testing, and performance optimization.
- Implement precise designs based on Sketch specs provided by the design team.
- Skills and technologies: Angular.js, Koa.js, Webpack, Karma, Protractor

## **University of Leipzig**

Leipzig, Germany

Research Associate (NLP Chair) – 2013-2014

- Developed front-end and back-end for language learning application, called *Ancient Geek*, based on morphosyntactic data (e.g. parse trees and aligned texts).
- Components include an assisted reading environment, parse tree editor, alignment editor, and lesson generator. Also developed the API and deployment scripts.
- Internationalized application for LTR and RTL languages.
- Skills and technologies: Backbone.js, d3.js, Gulp, Mocha, Jasmine, Django, Django Tastypie, Neo4j, Postgres, Nginx, Fabric

### iPlant Collaborative

Tucson, Arizona

User Experience Developer – 2012-2013

- Developed user interface for iPlant's Cloud Services platform, *Atmosphere*, including functionality for creating and managing instances, images, and volumes.
- Led project-wide effort to evaluate usability of existing applications; advocated for and assisted in implementing improvements, considering information architecture, user-application interaction, and design.
- Skills and technologies: Backbone.js, d3.js, Linux

### Student Webmaster - 2010-2012

- Designed and developed internal user management application.
- Designed posters, fliers, brochures, infographics, presentation templates, and explanatory models for publications.
- Created UI prototypes and coded cross-browser compatible, standards-compliant web applications, as well as design elements needed for their implementation.
- Skills and technologies: PHP, MySQL, CAS integration

# Education University of Arizona

Tucson, Arizona

BA Classics, Computer Science minor, *cum laude* – 2008-2012

- Academic achievements: Wildcat Excellence Award (Academic scholarship, 2008-2012), Sallie Mae Scholarship Essay Winner (2009), placed in National Greek Exam (2011).
- Extracurricular: Member of Eta Sigma Phi, the National Classics Honorarium (2011-2012). Also a member of the Classics Club (2011-2012).
- Languages studied (semesters): Latin (7), Ancient Greek (4), French (3), Japanese (2)
- Computer Science subjects taken: Object-oriented programming and design (Java), Computational Linguistics (Python), Unix and systems programming (C), Computer architecture (Assembly), web programming

Conference talks

https://monicalent.com/speaking

Presentations

Digital Classicist Berlin - 2013

Berlin, Germany

Co-presented at a seminar on user experience for historical languages eLearning.

University of Arizona IT Summit - 2013

Tucson, Arizona

Co-presented on user experience design and front-end development for Atmosphere, the iPlant Collaborative's cloud platform for scientists.

Core Skills JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Linux, Vim, Tmux

Languages English (native – US citizen), German (conversational)

Hobbies Photography, travel, cooking, blogging

References Available upon request